Today we're going to talk about the only
businesses left to build in the agentic
era. Yes, I think that there's only 13
businesses to be building in the world
of agents. Now, I don't subscribe to the
people who say there's going to be this
permanent underclass and you just got to
create businesses or else you're kind of
messed up for the future. I don't think
it's going to be as dire as that, but I
do think that in you know, in a world
where agents exist, abundance are going
to exist, owning these assets, I mean,
are going to put you just in a better
position. So, today what are we going to
do?
We're going to go through the 13
businesses that are left to be built. By
the end of this you're going to
understand all 13 pretty well,
>> [music]
>> why why there's an opportunity, why
they're going to exist in a world of
agents, couple ideas. So, but you know,
grab your coffee, grab your tea, strap
in because
hey, [music] this is the stuff that, you
know, if you're in your teenager, if
you're in 20s, your 30s, 50s, 70s, this
is good stuff to know
>> [music]
>> because the world is changing and it is
changing fast.
>> [music]
>> So,
the first type of business
that, you know, you'd want to own in an
AI agent world is AI native service
firms. What is that? Well, an AI native
service firm firm is when the agents do
more of the delivery. Now, I've seen
people say AI native service firms is
when they do all of the delivery. I
don't believe that's the case. I think
you can still have
the agent doing 90% of the work
and still be an AI native firm. So, as
an example, you can create a bookkeeping
firm for one type of business where, you
know, you have client records, the
agents prepare the books, and then the
human reviews exceptions, and then you
complete monthly books. And you charge
for the completed job. It could be a a
monthly fee, but it could also be, "Hey,
every time we, you know, complete these
books,
it's going to cost XYZ."
Um
why is owning this business good? Well,
it's high margin. Uh you don't need that
many clients. Um the why now exists when
you have uh you know,
uh Astra, uh 5.5,
um some of these great models that are
are coming out soon.
Um
you know, you actually they, you know,
could get this incredible amount of
output. So, I'm really interested in
AI-native service firms. I did a whole
episode on one recently. I'll include it
in the description
um around creating a creative agency.
So, you can imagine doing like a logos
as a service or or ads as a service,
these sorts of things. Really like these
businesses, super high margin, uh and
something I'm ideating actively around.
The second is just generally offline
businesses.
Um you know, people Yes, it's an AI age,
but we, you know, people actually want
to pay to go and do something with other
people. So, uh one example of this is um
you know, this this company called
Othership. I heard about them from the
founder actually in Toronto where they
started. Um and they've got this like
neighborhood sauna club where there's
you know, you walk into the sauna and
it's like huge and there's other people
and there's music uh and they, you know,
there's someone who can help you do cold
plunges and it's just this incredible
environment and tea.
Um they basically leveled up the
experience of a communal sauna. And I
think now more than ever
uh
you know, people want this sort of
thing. And it's not cheap. It's really
not. Um the visit itself could be, you
know, I don't I don't remember exactly
what it is, but it's it's not cheap.
Um but it's an incredible experience and
they sell a membership. So, I think
businesses like this that, you know, are
on to uh trends, um
you know, here the trends are obviously
are wellness,
um community,
um and you're just seeing them scale.
They've been scaling in New York and I
just I love these types of businesses,
um especially ones that have a
membership model. So, I think you're
going to see a lot more like this. Um
and you can run, you know, of course you
can have agents do a lot of the admin,
but the room, the experience is what
people are buying. Now, the hard part
about offline businesses, obviously, is
that it costs a lot more money to start
an offline business than an AI-native
service firm, especially if you're
creating an offline business in a place
like Manhattan or Toronto, like place
with high amount of real estate. So, um
you know, how I think about offline
businesses is, you know, what is the
food cart version of uh or food truck.
What is the food truck version of your
business? What do I mean by that?
If you're going to start a restaurant,
sometimes the best thing to do is to
start a food truck version of it because
it's just so much cheaper,
um and you can prove out that model that
way. So,
um
the MVP, you know, what is the what does
that look like? And I actually think I
actually now that I'm remembering, I
remember speaking to the founder about
this,
the first version of Othership was
literally in the founder's backyard. He
literally like made this in his
backyard, and obviously that didn't cost
too much money. He started inviting
friends, community members, and then he
decided to get uh a place. So, take it
one step at a time.
Third is distribution. So, we live in
this world now where
you prompt a few times and all of a
sudden you basically have a startup, but
getting people to the products
that you're building or people are
building is uh
harder than ever, honestly. And my
belief is that the price of reaching
people is going to get higher and
higher. And actually, if you take a step
back and look at what people used to
charge for, for example, a Facebook ad.
In 2000 and
you know, nine or whatever, when the
Facebook ad platform came out, they were
literally charging 5 cents a click. Now,
the average click,
uh you know, I don't I don't have the
exact data in front of me, but we're
talking a dollar, two dollars, like
you know, even more than that. Three
dollars, four dollars, five dollars,
depending on who you're trying to target
and which country you're trying to
target.
So, I think that owning organic
audiences is so so so important, and I
think that even be you know, before you
end up, you know, if you end up wanting
to create an offline business, if you
end up wanting to create an AI native
service for a firm, starting with the
distribution, building organic
audiences, the cool part about this is
you can get paid
to generate, you you know, useful niche
information. You get paid by advertisers
to basically build your audience, and
then you go and build the products that
they ask for. This is something I call
the ACP funnel, audience community
product. First, you start with the
audience, then you build the community,
then you build the product. Um this is
something that, you know, is a business
model. I think people who own multiple
you know, meme pages, multiple uh
YouTube channels, multiple
uh uh
Instagram audiences, those people are
going to do well in this era. So, I
think number three, distribution. The
fourth, which is actually not talked
about that often, is proprietary
data sets. So, I think that uh what
you're what you're starting to see is
that data is just so valuable. Data is
the new oil. Um you know, there's
all these companies like Merch One,
Micro One who um
who are selling data to the big labs and
are getting in you know, insane
valuations, billions of dollars,
hundreds of millions of ARR. It's
absolutely insane. And so there's that
that's the big idea you know, at the big
idea
like level which is basically pay people
for data, get data that the big models
don't have and then uh
basically market up to the big labs, but
if you're just a you know, solo founder
and you don't want to go build something
that big and you want to create a
business that might generate a few
million dollars a year is just
how do you just get very useful
information
and that people cannot get by using
their personal agents or um
or going to chat GBT, that sort of
thing. And I think thinking about that
uh is a really really important thing.
Um
I think there's going to be this gold
rush for getting and acquiring data. I
think we're in the first inning of that
and this is just a business that you
know, if you own data you know, in this
AI world, you're looking really good.
The fifth is domain specific harnesses.
Now, I feel like a lot of people throw
the word harness around and like
honestly, people don't really understand
what it is.
Um so, I'm going to take a second to
explain to you in just as clear as I can
what a harness really means
and how is it different than a LLM
model. So, um you know, you can think
you can think of the model or I think of
the model as basically the engine of the
car. Um, how fast it goes, um, and I
think of the harness as the tools it can
access, the workflow rules, the memory,
the checks. Basically everything around
the the engine. Um,
and if we use the car analogy, we're
talking about like the body, we're
talking about the steering wheel, we're
talking about um, the floor mats, you're
talking about the color of the car, the
paint, you know, the electrical,
everything else. That's the easiest way
to explain it. It's not It's not a
perfect way of explaining it. You know,
I am missing a few things, but that's
like the general way to think about. So,
if you can take a
general model
and turn it into a system that
understands how an industry works, for
example, you know, the example I was
using is
the operating system for a freight
brokerage agent, you know, you're going
to be able to have a lot of value. You
know, we talked about the gold rush and
proprietary data sets. I think you're
also witnessing now this gold rush
around harnesses. I believe that
harnesses are the new GPT wrapper.
Two years ago, we saw a lot of people
create GPT wrappers. Initially, for
about 12 months, people were saying
GPT wrappers were useless. People
weren't going to weren't going to be
able to create any sort of lasting value
with it or any value with it. And we saw
quite the opposite. The well, we saw a
bunch of
uh
GPT wrappers go nowhere in the same way
that, you know, startups 90% fail. But I
think the top 10% a lot of what happened
is they turned into harnesses.
So, they were
they had they started as a a wrapper
focused on one model, and as that model
got better,
um,
that service got better, but they
started adding things like here. Like
they started adding industry tools and
workflow rules and memory and then they
became harnesses. An example of that
would be you saw a lot of that in the
legal space, Harvey, spell spellbook, I
think it's called.
So I expect to see a lot more of that. I
think there's a lot of opportunity
here and by the way, comment in the on
YouTube
for if you ever want me to go deeper
into any one of these, just let me know
and I can create dedicated videos
with some ideas and that sort of thing.
And also, while you're at it, like this
and if you're on Spotify or Apple,
please rate rate it five stars cuz we
got some a few low stars
so from from back in the day. So let's
try to get it up. The sixth is
robotics and physical AI. So
this one
a lot of people think that it is so far
away in the future that it's like the
Jetsons.
Just like really in the future, but I
don't think people realize that we are
like almost there. I saw this new
product called Osmo. I think they raised
like six or seven million dollars
recently
and they are literally doing window
cleaning as a service.
So building owners pay for clean windows
and then you deploy and operate the
equipment
or they they deploy and operate the the
equipment and it's just a beautiful
business, right? The hard part is
obviously building these companies,
right? But I think that you're going to
see a lot more robotics and physical AI
and actually the best way to I saw a
really good tweet by my friend Brian
Norgard and he said I think the best way
to sell software is by
selling hardware and I think you're
going to see a lot of that. So a lot
more businesses like that and for the
people listening who are like, I'm not
going to go and create a robotics
company. What do I know about, you know,
all this
PhD stuff. Well, I think there's going
to be an opportunity for you to maybe
buy a few and rent it to people, or buy,
you know, if you're into sales, you can
go and sell them. You know, there's a
lot of opportunity. It doesn't
necessarily
mean you need to be an Elon Musk
character to go and like figure out what
these things are and build them. You can
also be on the sales, marketing side,
and I think there's going to be a ton of
opportunity. Number six.
Number seven, uh
physical products with a fan following.
Um so, this is the I'm sure a lot of you
know that I love coffee, um
and I'm a bit of a nerd like that.
Um specialty coffee equipment is um
an example of like people get like so
nerdy about it, and they're willing to
pay high prices for well-designed
things.
Um
and when Fellow came out, like there was
nothing like this. A lot of the This is
um a kettle.
So, a lot of the kettles didn't really
feel like they were designed for coffee
people. And then this came out, and it
started, you know, that they started
crushing it, and now they have a huge
product suite of different
um
of different products. Like I got a uh
Fellow grinder back there. By the way,
not affiliated with
with Fellow. Just just
again, like a fan. Um and uh I think
there's a ton of opportunity to just
like create these niche products. I also
think with
um
hard
uh just AI, like for example, uh
you know, Astra and the latest new
models, you can actually
design hardware and physical products
That were too niche before,
you can go and do that now. So if you
have the insight for a particular fan
following or particular ICP, you can go
and buy I think the device is like the
bamboo.
It's a Chinese device and you can go and
like prototype um
some of these new products and then, you
know, obviously mass produce it, sell
it.
Another friend of mine uh
our friend of mine started something
called the Minimal Company and those are
phones that are focused on people who
don't want to scroll and I think they
they did millions of dollars on their uh
Kickstarter. Again, that's like a fan
following. I you know, Apple's not
creating that product. So there's a lot
of opportunity. I think there's a lot of
pent-up demand for specific
products here. um
And especially the ones that can go
viral in that niche. So if you have if
you have if you really understand a
niche
that was a really good time. I really do
want to do an episode around like
physical products, how to use AI to
create them. So hopefully you guys are
into that. Um number eight, compute and
energy. um We can't forget that every
agent needs chips, electricity, cooling
and somewhere to run. So if you own that
scarce input um hey, that is a good
place to be. Saw just the other week
Crusoe raised 3.9 billion dollars for
its vertically integrated
AI infrastructure platform. um
So you're just seeing that. I think uh
Michael Dell's son uh is raising
billions of dollars for his, you know,
energy uh company. um You're just seeing
people people need compute, people need
energy. These are the scarce inputs of
our time. So, if there's any way that
you can go and
uh
be involved in some of these businesses,
probably do pretty well.
Number nine, health, longevity, uh and
care. Uh I I've talked a lot about on
the Startup Ideas podcast, on this
podcast, about
uh older adults. I think older adults
are missing
It's just like a an ICP that a lot of
people, especially younger people, are
not creating for, but they need
products, they need services,
um and there's, you know, any way we can
make their lives happier and healthier,
I think would be a great thing. So, I
think there's tons of ideas, products,
services, um
that are actually high-quality, that
have a high NPS, that are exceptional,
that you could be creating,
um
and then also, from a service business
perspective, care, uh there's a lot of
opportunity there.
Um help helping older adults,
um
and and just like owning agencies in
that space,
uh for example, caregivers and things
like that. Lot here,
um
and uh obviously
hard businesses to do, a lot of those
service businesses to run,
um but great great businesses, and also,
you know, you're doing a good thing by
caring for for folks. And then the
longevity piece, I mean, I feel like
Bryan Johnson really kicked off this
whole, you know, don't die movement. Um
he really Well, he didn't kick it off,
he kind of tapped into it. He he He was
like, "I'm the guy."
Um
so, you know, health, maybe that was
Huberman, longevity, maybe that was uh
Bryan Johnson.
Um there's still opportunity to go and
be the gal or guy in that space if you
just, you know, I go down and niche
niche down. But point is, there's a lot
of opportunity here, a lot of business
to be create to be created, and I think
a lot of un
a lot of demand to tap into.
The 10th is marketplaces and social
networks. Now, a lot of people are not
creating these products and startups
anymore. When I first came to Silicon
Valley, uh
it was just the thing. We're talking
2013, 2014, 2015, that era. You know,
creating things like Uber, which
matched, you know, drivers and
customers. Creating things like
Thumbtack, which was like services
to find a handyman and and things like
that. And social networks, Instagram,
TikTok,
things like that. Uh, the thing is
I I On one hand, I love these businesses
cuz if you're able to create it, you do
truly have a moat.
But liquidity, meaning
making sure you have both the demand and
supply at the same time, is an art. I
feel like marketplaces and social
network is more art than science in that
way.
But I think there's tons of
opportunities right now. Mark Lou, who
some of you know, had you know, created
a marketplace around selling startups
and buying startups, trustmr.com. So,
you're starting to see people come back
to marketplaces and social networks, but
I feel like it's a great thing to own,
co-own,
be a part of if you can. Personal agents
are going to want to access
marketplaces, they're going to want to
access social networks. The data that
comes from both these things are really
interesting. I love these businesses, so
had to put it in there as well. I I just
in general, just like real assets.
Um so the example I have here is small
industrial workshops rented to local
trades. You know, in trades in general
by the way, like electricians, cabinet
makers, plumbers,
um physical assets, warehouses,
uh
you know, industrial industrial
warehouses, things like that. Uh we
forgot, you know, we can't forget that,
you know, you need a place to have a
location,
a property for a lot of the new world
that we're entering in. So literally
physical locations and real
real assets, real estate, I think
still going to be a really interesting
business. Vertical agents, number 12. So
just giving an agent responsibility for
a recurring job in a specific industry.
The example I have here is purchasing
for indie restaurants.
So you have checking stock, comparing
supply offers, ask for approval, place
the order. I feel like people have been
building vertical agents for the last
like
12 months, but I still think there's a
ton of opportunity
um
to build like we talked about harnesses
and to build uh agents. And last but not
least is security.
Uh people need security more than ever
in the AI age. Now I'm talking about two
types of security. I'm talking about
software companies like one password.
Uh I'm talking about, you know,
companies like Cloudflare
uh who have a lot of security
AI features. I'm talking about, you
know, the example I have here, agent
access control for accounting firms that
allow you to just read invoices and
draft entries that would allow, you
know, allow you to do that. Um but
basically
uh thinking about sensitive workflows
and then working through firms' existing
IT providers and just having access
controls so that data doesn't get leaked
and things don't get hacked and things
like that. I think that's a one piece of
it.
Uh just security in the agentic era,
things are going to get hacked. This is
going to be more and more of a problem.
You know, I think I wouldn't be
surprised if one of the personal agent
startups um
or just agent startups, like there's
like a a big a big hack security breach
uh and things get put on the internet. I
think that might happen. Um I think it's
going to happen. I think it's actually
it's it's it's going to happen more and
more. So, people are going to want
security and owning those assets and
businesses are going to be great. And
then like actually security in general,
like I think there's like a
Uber, forget the name of it, but it's
like Uber for like you know, bodyguards
and you know, you get a car and it's
like bulletproof and stuff like that. I
think there's going to be more of those
businesses. People feel less and less
secure.
So, they're just going to want to pay
for security in general. A lot of
security businesses, I'm really
interested. And that's that's what I'd
want to own in this world. I mean, I'm
not saying, like I said in the
beginning, not saying to escape the
permanent under crust, you need a own a
piece of this, but I am saying
these are the only businesses that are
left. Owning a piece of these businesses
are
going to set you up. Um and this is
where it's at. This is a map of the ones
that I would pay attention to, the 13
ones,
uh the best ones.
Um
and I hope that this has gotten your
creative juices flowing.
Um please do let me know. Uh I read
every single comment. I reply to most on
on YouTube. And thank you for giving me
your time. Um
I don't take that lightly. I I think
it's amazing I can just come on here and
be like, "Hey, I think that these are
the 13 businesses uh left the only
businesses left to build." And some of
you are going to take that in and it's
going to impact your lives. Um
and that's really cool. So, thank you
again. You're the best. I'm rooting for
you and I'll see you next time.